# **Arun Saravanan**

Senior Technical Lead

Skilled UI Lead specialising in Javascript and well-versed in Angular, HTML5 and React. Expertise in requirement gathering and analysis, architectural, component and interface design and development using agile methodologies for web-based applications in multiple domains. Insightful professional ready to apply 14 years of experience to new role with room for growth and advancement.

#### **Personal Info**

#### Location

Chennai, INDIA

#### Phone

+91 9894076338

#### E-mail

arunsaravanan.n@gmail.com

#### Portfolio

https://arunsaravanan.com

## **Skills**

Angular Proficient React Competent **Javascript Expert** HTML5 **Expert** CSS3 Competent Node.js Proficient **REST** Proficient JSON Schema Proficient MEAN Stack Competent MERN Stack Competent **jQuery** 

#### **Education**

## B.E. - Computer Science And Engineering

Competent

R.V.S. College of Engineering And Technology, Dindigul (Affiliated to Anna University, Chennai)

#### **Years of Study**

2002 - 2006

# Work History

# 2016-03 -

Current

HCL Technologies Ltd., Chennai, Tamilnadu

Senior Technical Lead

- Working as an UI SME for major US Telecom client in developing business to business portals
- Developed dashboards for Public Safety Monitoring, Smart Parking and Smart City solutions using IoT platform
- Created rapid prototype UI components and dashboards to fast track PoC development
- Evaluated and adopted new technologies and frameworks to address changing UI needs
- Managed a team of 4 UI developers focused on initiating and implementing a data fulfilment portal for TV Shows based ecommerce start-up

## 2013-02 - Senior Developer 2016-02 7izera (formerly EC Sof

Zizera (formerly EC Software), Chennai, Tamilnadu

- Developed HTML5/Javascript and Flash based online catalogue viewer applications extracted from PDF publications with rich interactive experience and developed HTML content as a service/component in Mobile web and native hybrid applications
- Worked on catalogue viewer for International clients IKEA, Sandvik, Oriflame and Teng tools

### 2009-07 - Senior Developer

2013-01

2009-06

Dot Com Infoway Pvt. Ltd., Madurai, Tamilnadu

 Developed interactive web/mobile applications using Adobe Flash/Flex, HTML and jQuery/jQuery Mobile Framework

## 2008-10 - Junior Programmer

Prism New Media Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Chennai, Tamilnadu

 Developed and Maintained Digital Signage and KIOSK Touch Screen based way finder applications using Adobe Flash, HTML and XML

# 2008-03 - Cyber Flash Scripter

2008-09

Cyber School Technology Solutions, Chennai, Tamilnadu

 Developed Flash interactive courses for activities in Digital Science and Mathematics in school level. Compiled and managed interactive courses in LMS environment

#### 2006-06 - Executive Intern

2007-05

Riddhi Consulting, Chennai, Tamilnadu

- Developed and maintained a website for HR consulting
- Conducted online campaign for job fairs
- Provided day-to-day IT support and information management